Vanessa Pratnicki

Baltimore, Maryland (443) 220-3820 vanessa@pratnicki.net

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished Web Content Manager with over 8 years of experience in web content development, management, editorial work and leadership. Lead a team of over 100 Sitecore content collaborators and contributors, with a strong background in web technology, multimedia applications, and usability and accessibility techniques. Effective communicator with the ability to work efficiently with individuals and teams at all levels of an organization.

COMPETENCIES

Browser Based Technologies

- HTML. CSS
- JavaScript/jQuery
- Responsive Design
- Bootstrap
- Handlebars
- Local Storage, Session Storage, IndexDB
- React.js
- **Databases**
- MySQL
- Server Side development
- User Authentication
- Progressive Web Applications (PWAs)
- **API Interaction**
- API, JSON & AJAX
- Additional skills/technologies
- MS Office and the Adobe Creative Suite
- Project management
- Quality assurance

- Content management systems (CMS): Sitecore, WordPress and Cascade
- Google Analytics
- Web/PDF accessibility
- SEO
- User Experience (UX)Design
- Information architecture
- Web design
- MongoDB
- MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

- Web Content Standards
- ADA Standards for Accessible Design

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Web Content Manager - June, 2014 to Present Community College of Baltimore County - Baltimore, MD

- Sitecore CMS administrator for ccbcmd.edu.
- Provide leadership to over 100 Sitecore content contributors and owners to ensure all website content is accurate, up-to-date, and adheres to Web Content Standards and the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) Standards for Accessible Design.
- Conduct content audits to monitor, evaluate and apply feedback to ensure content is current, relevant, effective and conforms to best practices and college website standards.
- Provide in-depth, web content management training, including developing curriculum and materials, such as video tutorials, documentation, exercises, and assessments.
- Articulate and communicate to the web team regarding assignments, projects, milestones, program issues under review, deadlines and time frames for completion.
- Facilitate multi-step process of on-boarding new content contributors and owners into Sitecore, from designation of content responsibilities to granting permissions and creating workflows within Sitecore.
- Test features and work with the Web Developer to implement website enhancements.
- Create and maintain the Web Management Team's operating procedures and documentation.
- Develop, maintain, and distribute standard operating procedures for all CCBC content collaborators, contributors, and owners. This includes establishing and maintaining a community of current CCBC web users.

Degree Audit Technician - April, 2008 to June, 2014 **Community College of Baltimore County** - Baltimore, MD

- Developed best practice standards for the degree audit systems to ensure that all content is consistent, clear and provides the best user experience.
- Experience using CCBC's in-house customized content management system. Designated content responsibilities for the Graduation/Commencement sections of the public facing website.
- Promoted the Degree Audit system to the CCBC community through various mediums, including the creation of brochures, training materials, and online resources.
- Conducted formal and informal campus wide training sessions to CCBC faculty, staff and students; presenting at Professional Development Day conferences and adjunct faculty conferences.

Graduation Specialist - October, 2005 to April, 2008 **Community College of Baltimore County** - Baltimore, MD

- Implemented the launch of CAPP and DegreeWorks (degree audit programs); programmed all course requirements using Boolean logic.
- Responsible for articulating college policies and procedures to students, colleagues, and the general public over the phone and in person.
- Collaborated with various individuals within the CCBC community, including facility, program coordinators, Deans, Vice-Presidents and other departments.
- Knowledge of approximately 1,500 courses and programs for both credit and non-credit course offerings.

Information Specialist - January, 2005 to October, 2005 **Community College of Baltimore County** - Baltimore, MD

- Served as the front line representative to the college community and the public community regarding CCBC credit and non-credit course offerings.
- Provided prospective students, current students, businesses, faculty and staff with general and registration information and advisement concerning Continuing Education courses, programs and services.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development - Certificate
The George Washington University

Mass Communication, Advertising track - Bachelor of Science Towson University

- Graduated in the top 10th percentile
- Member of the Golden Key International Honour Society and the Lambda Pi Eta Mass Communication Honors Society

General Studies - Associate of Arts Community College of Baltimore County

• Magna Cum Laude

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

National Council for Marketing and Public Relations (NCMPR) Medallion awards

• Gold Medallion: SmartREACH microsite, 2017

Silver Medallion: Website, 2017
Silver Medallion: Microsite, 2016
Bronze Medallion: Website, 2015

CCBC Enrollment and Student Services Leadership Program

May 2014

Program highlights:

- A host of experienced leaders shared knowledge and insights about critical issues facing High Education, such as budgeting, governance, advocacy, communication and organizational strategy.
- Participated in a variety of practical leadership applications, including a year-long intensive team project presented to Senior Staff, to resolve a critical challenge facing ESS.

CERTIFICATIONS

Accessibility for Content Contributors and Designers Certificate
Mastering Web Optimization with Siteimprove Certificate